### Zulfiya Silko

+44 (0) 7908 478687 / zulfiya.silko@gmail.com / Bedford, MK40 1BS

An engineer with four years of experience in developing software in Java and most recently – one year of practising HTML, CSS, JS, PHP and Laravel. Relocated to the UK and joined a small web design agency in 2018. Grasped full stack of web technologies and willing to gain work experience in the UK. Capable of delivering results within tight deadlines, always open to new ideas and opportunities.

#### **KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Created and launched a complete set of documentation for 'iRule' analytical enterprise software.
- Switched to the role of Java Developer and has successfully launched integrations with three external data suppliers through APIs.
- Joined a web design agency in the role of Junior Web Developer and contributed to the successful launch of six commercial web projects over the last year.

#### **EDUCATION**

# NRNU MEPHI: Automated Information Processing and Management Specialist, Moscow, Russia (Sep 2009 – Jul 2014)

- Math analysis, probability theory, discrete math; physics; coding theory; databases; C++, information systems design; digital data processing, networks.
- Diploma project: laboratory work unit for students with a programmable matrix screen.

#### **CAREER HISTORY**

## Supersonic Media: Junior Web Developer, remote work (Oct 2018 – present), Cranfield, UK

- Developed HTML and CSS layouts with Sass/Less and Gulp according to Figma mockups;
- Created models, controllers, views, migrations and seeders for Laravel projects;
- Contributed to successful launch of six web projects: <u>viscapital.co.uk</u>, <u>prfc.ru</u>, <u>fabrika.center</u>, <u>honestmusic.ru</u>, <u>chemagrotrade.moscow</u>, <u>lightcom.msk.ru</u>.

#### Security Problems Institute: Java Developer (Jun 2016 - Sep 2018), Moscow, Russia

- Has successfully launched integrations with three external data suppliers through their APIs:
  Bureau van Dijk (Swiss), OpenCorporates and TASS News Agency. Had been responsible for the
  full cycle of the integration: gathering requirements, delivering code and providing support.
- Focused on Java coding and used frameworks such as Spring, Hibernate ORM and Maven.

#### Security Problems Institute: Technical Writer (Oct 2014 - May 2016), Moscow, Russia

- Launched a complete set of documentation for <u>'iRule'</u> vast analytical enterprise software and the SPI's main product. Gathered data from stakeholders and explored the system beforehand.
- Implemented user manuals in an interactive HTML way with 'Help+Manual', Git and SVN.

#### SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Sass/Less, BEM technology, Sketch, Figma.
- Back-end: PHP, Laravel 5.x, MySQL
- VSC: Git, SVN. Build: Gulp, NPM, Composer.
- Java; Maven, Hibernate, Spring Boot; PL/SQL
- 'Help+Manual' tech documentation writing skills;
- Languages: English, Russian.
- Mac user; Bass and piano player.